<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yevhen orlov</title>
    <description># Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this # line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for # Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yevhenorlov.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 23:05:13 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 23:05:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>[summary] interview with dan fox</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…One thought experiment I enjoy doing is taking a massively popular, best-selling album or film and trying to describe it without naming the artist or title, and see if it sounds pretentious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hit me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance: a concept album about an imaginary Edwardian military band, featuring songs written in a number of styles ranging from psychedelic rock, through Indian classical music, to European avant-garde composition, and vaudeville. Its cover features Karl Marx, Carl Jung, Marlene Dietrich, and Karlheinz Stockhausen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think I know this one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s Sgt Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club Band by The Beatles, an album that sounds remarkably pretentious when you remove the band name, when you take away the associations we have with that name—of global popularity, of a celebrated British export, of a high point in 1960s pop culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context is everything, then.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretentiousness is a driving force in art, because it entails risk—the risk of over-stretching your ability, of perhaps falling flat on your face. But if you played it safe all the time, you’d never get anywhere interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vice.com/read/dan-fox-why-pretentiousness-matters&quot;&gt;http://www.vice.com/read/dan-fox-why-pretentiousness-matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 09:56:07 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/02/28/dan-fox.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/02/28/dan-fox.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[summary] interview with 0pn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…a way of me being honest with myself about stuff. I need my “art work” or “entertainment work” or whatever to have empathy for or connection to the way I experience the world as a person. I have a hard time making a linear-idea song, because that’s not the way my thoughts work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I think I do all this cool shit but to the average celebrity I’m at best a magician or clown. Then again you just totally complimented me on seeming wantless, which I didn’t notice because I was so busy feeling humiliated. Is that something you want for yourself, to be wantless? Like a chill object floating in space?…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I’m materialistic but in the name of distracting myself to death. I really don’t care if anyone thinks I’m special or not, I just want to be able to live my life without thinking about money all the time, or where I’m going to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…you are looking to make music that will “grow with you as you get older” rather than music geared to a “get addicted to it and throw it away” mentality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I’m hurt by music all the time. I’m hurt pretty much every time I turn on Vevo. I can love formal aspects of music without any kind of emotional commitment so it’s not like bad songwriting or bad arrangement or production hurts me. It’s the bullshit around music that hurts me. My friend Arthur (Autre Ne Veut), the whole conceit of his new record is that we’re all dying to buy into the performance of honesty. We’ll pay money to see an artist say something in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…it’s just that most celebrities’ idea of honesty is so tedious. They’re asking “why” a lot and then crying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vice.com/read/fuck-music-lets-talk-about-feelings-an-interview-with-oneohtrix-point-never&quot;&gt;http://www.vice.com/read/fuck-music-lets-talk-about-feelings-an-interview-with-oneohtrix-point-never&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 21:37:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2015/11/16/0pn.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2015/11/16/0pn.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[summary] interview with dextro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.generateddesign.com/we-talked-with-dextro-one-of-the-most-elusive-algorithmic-artists/&quot;&gt;He was also annoyed with the tendency of artists to promote themselves, rather than let the work speak for itself, as well as artists’ tendency “to address the ratio or intellect of their audience rather than their intuition or subconscious.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 17:47:47 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2015/10/25/dextro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2015/10/25/dextro.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
