<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yevhen orlov</title>
    <description># Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this # line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for # Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yevhenorlov.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 09:49:58 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 09:49:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with aaron oppenheim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…I do not use any MIDI controllers or anything. Early at Mills I made that decision inspired by Ikue Mori’s setup. She visited in my first or second week at Mills, and talked about her stuff. She does not use controllers because it is just simpler and more portable. If you are carrying around a MIDI keyboard every time you play a gig, it is another thing to take with you, it is another thing to break, you can lose it or you just forget to bring it or something like that. What do you do? You cannot play. So many people who do live computer music their systems crash, computers crash, something is not working right, things like that. The more peripherals you add the more likely you will have a technical issue. So I just decided to not have any peripherals and just use the laptop. My controls are all the computer keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…the other thing about laptop improvisation is that you are building your instrument at the same time as you are learning to play it. When I was starting out I would add some functionality but then I would have to learn to play that in a musical way. Not only was my system not very well thought out, well programmed or finished, I also was not good at playing it at the beginning. It took a while to develop some ability and remember how to do things and have everything available without having to think about it, that was another thing. It was important to make it easy to start to make a sound so that I would not have to think about it, if you have to think about it before making sound then you lose the intuition, really quick responses and the kind of dialogue you can have when you have this immediate ability to do something. It was also a matter of just practice and playing and learning the instrument that I made and its capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…Originally I actually wanted to do more synthesis because I like synthesis and also when I was thinking about the aesthetics of electronic music I was like, “what is the point of using samples because it will just sound like something else. It can sound like another instrument but I could always just get someone else to play that instrument. Why should my computer sound like a piano, it should sound like a computer so I will do synthesis, it is electronic not an acoustic instrument”. In doing that I found my sound very limited and it was hard to shift very quickly. Just changing the bottom of the chain into samples allowed me to switch really fast into something else. Then by just applying a lot of processes and the granulation it still sounds very electronic, you would not confuse my stuff for an actual piano even if I am playing a piano sample because I will do a lot of things to it and it does not sound anything like the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I am always back and forth on whether or not I like doing live sampling but I do do it. Sometimes I do not like the way other people do that, I feel like it can be a kind of easy cheap effect and sometimes musicians do not like it if you sample them while they are playing, if they can tell you are doing that it will confuse them. It has happened to me several times where I have sampled someone and shifted them or something and if they can tell they are being sampled it will snap them out of what they are doing a lot of the time. If I am sampling live I will want to manipulate it so that it creates this responsive sound and it is not clear that it is from them directly because if it is just sort of echoing them, following along or whatever it often really confuses them. Also my feeling is if I am just sampling them and affecting them I am just an effect pedal. What is the point of me being there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…It is definitely related to science. That was always a criticism that people made of Alvin Lucier that it was not really music it was just science experiments or something which I thought was really stupid. But it is true that in his stuff especially, there is this element that is so minimal and he has such clear process based music. He has a very musical sense and he knows what he is doing, he came to Mills one year, I spent quite a bit of time with him and he thinks musically he does not think in terms of science, he does these literally experimental pieces and process pieces because he thinks it will have a musical effect not because he thinks it will be cool. He thinks it will sound nice, interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://experinautas.com/interviews/aaron-oppenheim-laptop-based-improvisation/&quot;&gt;http://experinautas.com/interviews/aaron-oppenheim-laptop-based-improvisation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 21:06:28 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/08/17/aaron-oppenheim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/08/17/aaron-oppenheim.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with aleksi perälä</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“…You know that feeling when you hear a really amazing song and your hairs go up on your body? Colundi is that feeling all the time. It’s… it’s so amazing. So amazing.” He hesitates for a long time. “Also very, very difficult to put into words.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…A self-described “country bumpkin,” he thinks the common ground is upbringing. Just as Wilson-Claridge and Richard D. James reimagined techno in remote Cornwall, Perälä’s encounters with the second summer of love, via Finnish radio at the age of 12, were influenced by his rural location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s the whole beauty,” he says. “Because you hear only a few tracks that define the genre for you. And you want to hear more but you can’t. You can tape some stuff off the radio but not enough. So that’s what made me want to start making music. To fill in the gaps.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…Perälä was keen to share his discoveries, demonstrating on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ovuca.com/research.html&quot;&gt;his site&lt;/a&gt; how he constructed a series of equal temperament scales, dividing the octave into an increasing number of equally spaced steps. “It all started from 33hz and then built up from that,” he explains. “From just one frequency per octave, I went to using two frequencies per octave, then three, four, five all the way up to 32.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…Perälä’s epiphany is like any epiphany: utterly real to the person who experienced it, incomprehensible to those who didn’t. The difference with Colundi is that it’s also produced some extraordinary music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.residentadvisor.net/features/2567&quot;&gt;https://www.residentadvisor.net/features/2567&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 17:03:19 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/06/30/aleksi-perala.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/06/30/aleksi-perala.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with autechre 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you say the studio takes up most of your time. How is that for you? Is it gruelling, or enjoyable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sean Booth: Oh, I’m one of those weird guys who’d do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob Brown: It’s definitely habit forming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sean Booth: It’s fully addictive. If I have a choice of going out or staying in and doing some patching, I’ll almost always choose staying in unless I’m under a lot of pressure to go out. Takes quite a lot to get me out of here. I mean, I’m not socially that bad, but I just really, really like making music. I don’t have to make any effort to get stuck in here. If I did I’d probably get a teaching job or something because I’d need something else in life, but I don’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You even enjoy it if it’s just experimenting with software and you haven’t got anything resembling a track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sean Booth: I’ll be totally honest, there’s parts of what we do that are really fucking irritating. If I’m trying to build something and it’s not working but I can’t work out what the bug is, and I spend a month debugging it—that’s not that unusual—then I’ll be really fucking banging my head against a brick wall for a month. It’s a horrible feeling. But what you get at the end of it, when you’ve solved the problem and finally figured out that stupid mistake you made five weeks ago that you could easily have avoided—well, we’re back to learning. You’ve immediately learned. If I could do it and not have that, ever, it would be better, though. But I’m happy with it, warts and all. And when it is working, it’s all set up, then doing tracks on it… well, there’s nothing like it. It’s amazing. So it’s a compulsion, I suppose. I don’t see that as being gruelling. It’s really invigorating, and whatever the opposite of gruelling is— life affirming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…if you’re doing art, you have to consider the medium a lot. With this store thing that we’ve constructed, we wanted to be conscious of what it was and how it worked, because if we were just flinging albums up on there it would be a meaningless thing. There is a set of liberties that you can exploit if you’ve got that facility. I mean, I’ve been following various kids on SoundCloud and they’ll upload 50 tracks in a day. No artist in any other context would do this, but on SoundCloud nobody’s there to tell them that this is wrong. We also quite like the chapters thing, like you have if you’re doing marathon TV watching. Like, if I’m watching some big mainstream show like Game Of Thrones, I’ll watch four or five of them in a row on a Sunday afternoon—and that’s no longer weird for people to do that. So I guess we’re making music for people who’ll do things like that, who want to be completist and check out the whole of a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.residentadvisor.net/features/2756&quot;&gt;https://www.residentadvisor.net/features/2756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 16:04:08 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/06/11/autechre3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/06/11/autechre3.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} zen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/zen/comments/4lkgrr/who_are_the_most_important_posters_to_ignore_on/d3o31ht&quot;&gt;…Do you think clearing up your confusion using your conceptual mind will bring you any closer to the realization talked about in Zen? Have you considered just dwelling in the confusion until it can no longer sustain itself?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 02:03:25 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/zen/2016/05/30/zen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/zen/2016/05/30/zen.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>zen</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with autechre 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pitchfork: Once you guys were asked about progress and you said that every record was an asymptotic approach to something– that there wasn’t a perfect Autechre record, just a series of tangential curves towards and away from the same point…is that point itself in motion? Is it changing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autechre: We’re kind of following it, so yeah, it’s traveling but not with any given trajectory. It’s bouncing around. It’s confined by moving walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…We work for about a year, usually a bit longer, on an album, and then pick out tracks from what we’ve done that seem to have a thread, and then put them into an order. Then if there’s any changes that need making, a snip here and there, then we make them and there you go, that’s the album…But it never gets defined in language up until the point that we start doing interviews. Not by us, certainly. And only by inference and conversation, you know, some journalist saying “these tracks feel really…. whatever” and you just sit there saying “Okay”. [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…People’s focus– you can’t ever take it for granted. It’s absolute. It’s essential. When you listen to a track your focus shifts and moves around within it; obviously, we’re really aware of that, and that’s a big part of what we do. [the track itself] is often not that complex, it’s just that the way that you listen to it is, the way that you are guided through it as you listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pitchfork.com/features/interview/6012-autechre/&quot;&gt;http://pitchfork.com/features/interview/6012-autechre/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:22:46 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/05/26/autechre2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/05/26/autechre2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with raster-noton</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…we need to survive [laughs], because it’s our lives. It’s not only a company, it’s really a vision for a whole life. You could call Raster-Noton a record label or a company, but in the end, for us, it’s much more like a platform to do what we want to do. I think it survived because it’s not a maximum profit-based idea. We want to release our music or music that we find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…We saw this with Mille Plateaux, for instance, where at some point they released four records every week. I think it was part of the problem they created on their own. We said, “We have a very limited audience, we would like that everybody is able to buy the CD. Let’s not put out four CDs a week. Let’s put out one CD a month.” So then people can still follow, and on a real budget it’s OK to buy one. Until today, we have releases that sell around 1000 copies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…we all have a very big backbone in visual arts. And if you look from the visual arts side, an artist’s career as we know the classic artist career, they work on one topic their whole life. They have their creative style. So for us, it was actually more normal that you create a kind of style, and that you stick with this style and you work on one topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…the main thing is that we’re trying to develop a language over the years of what we are. You say, you’ve worked all these years and you worked inside developing your own language. As a label we’ve done that. And I think this is a pure artistic idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.residentadvisor.net/features/2712&quot;&gt;https://www.residentadvisor.net/features/2712&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 07:52:47 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/05/20/raster-noton.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/05/20/raster-noton.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with keith fullerton whitman 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…I found a quick cheap and dirty way to make these neat little canons, little Bach-like motor rhythms, very straight, 16th note, 8th note, pulsing, beautiful sounds. It’s a very small part of the patch, it’s just like four oscillators, the slow one doing the rate of the melody and the other one doing the clocking of the melody, going through a quantiser. Simple, just a few modules. And then I play with that for a few weeks, and I’m getting good results. Detuning each oscillator so there’s static intervals in there, like static third, static fourths, octaves of course. And then I got to a set of rules within the piece the more I played with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…It was almost like the exploration itself dictated the piece more than I was as a composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…And then very slowly built it from one tiny little case with just eight modules, then one suitacase, then two suitcases, and then it just got ridiculous. In one year it went from the string quartet to like the Vienna Symphonic version of it. It’s no better, it’s just gets more complicated with the same tonality. And then I had drums, I was having this kick drum every ten beats, and hi-hat every, like, 17… it was getting like prime number things, it was getting Prog. It was Pentangle turns into Genesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewire.co.uk/in-writing/themire/20880/the-keith-fullerton-whitman-notebooks-&quot;&gt;http://www.thewire.co.uk/in-writing/themire/20880/the-keith-fullerton-whitman-notebooks-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 16:10:28 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/09/kfw2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/09/kfw2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with keith fullerton whitman</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…I got caught in that void of not really making music while I was learning the ins and outs of modular synthesis. It’s like building a jigsaw puzzle before you can appreciate the picture. I finished that rack in about 2001 or 2002, and then I started spending more time making music on that than the computer. You can stand at the modular and all it does is make sound. What a beautiful thing that is. No diversions, no Facebook, no email. That’s it. It only exists in its own world to make sound. There’s a morning like today, where I don’t want to face the world or get on the internet, so I turn on the modular and by the end of the day I’ll have five minutes of cool sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…In the modular world it seems like there’s a lot of focus on the instrument itself rather than on what sort of music comes out of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally. A lot of this gear-heavy talk is a product of gear-heavy music. It’s not necessarily always a good thing. The best music always transcends technique and whatever system you’re using. I get a lot of people sending me demos while I’m traveling, and a lot of it sounds like “I just got a modular,” and they give me one hundred copies of a CD. That’s cool, but I busted my ass for 15 years before I even thought about putting out a record. It’s weird now that it’s sped up to the point where within a week of getting an instrument, you’re expected to know how it works and then do something substantive with it. So there’s just so much straight up noise out there. People don’t even figure out the basic idea of what a thing does before they start something with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ableton.com/en/blog/keith-fullerton-whitman/&quot;&gt;https://www.ableton.com/en/blog/keith-fullerton-whitman/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 15:47:17 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/09/kfw.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/09/kfw.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with peter blasser</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…The great Egyptian myth of Osiris inspired your process and the acceptance of imperfection. Is any musical instrument ever perfectly made?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was cut up by his brother, and then put back together by Isis. His penis was lost so they used a crocodile penis. That is my mantra: “crocodile penis.” Yes, no instrument is perfectly made. You always have to put a crocodile penis on it at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://noisey.vice.com/blog/musical-toys-peter-blassers-diy-synths&quot;&gt;http://noisey.vice.com/blog/musical-toys-peter-blassers-diy-synths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 12:36:36 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/08/peter-blasser.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/08/peter-blasser.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>{summary} interview with steevio</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…When it comes to setting up for any live performance or studio jam, everything in Steevio’s sound begins with a drone made up of all the oscillators humming at once. Starting with a “fundamental” oscillator that will represent the lowest drone, later to perhaps become a kick drum or a bassline, Steevio will then tune each successive oscillator to a harmonic of that “fundamental.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the time I’m finished I’ve got all the oscillators in the modular droning,” he says, “and I will adjust them to the point where it’s giving me an emotion, and that comes from things happening in my life that make feel a certain way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the right mood has been set, Steevio uses filters to shut everything down to silence, but still those oscillators are continuing to drone away underneath the rest of the rig. In essence, all the musical sounds that you hear in the actual performance are just snippets of that original drone being allowed to peek through in a particular way. While he isn’t sure that everyone approaches a modular performance in this way, the setting of the harmonics in the drone are an essential part of creating music that reflects Steevio’s emotions at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all of the sound, all at once,” he says, “so if you can handle that, then you can handle little bits of it. There’s something fundamentally right about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xlr8r.com/features/2016/04/a-guide-to-modular-synthesis/&quot;&gt;https://www.xlr8r.com/features/2016/04/a-guide-to-modular-synthesis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 10:51:54 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/07/steevio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yevhenorlov.github.io/summary/music/2016/04/07/steevio.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
